Let’s move on to a list, a collection of items
in a defined order and, in many cases, the most
common data structure used in Python apps. For
our example, contained in this 125-list file,
I have started a list of state capitals, line 1,
according to the list of states in alphabetical
order, with Montgomery being the capital
of Alabama, Juneau for Alaska, and onward.
Notice the syntax for this list. Commas separate
values within the list, which is contained inside
of square brackets. The primary purpose of a list
is to store a list of values in a single variable.
The time-saving factor of having a list is that,
when you have a list of values you need to adjust,
you don’t need to declare a variable for every
value. As we will see in the upcoming topic on
list operations, it takes very little code
to add and remove from a list, thus, again,
avoiding having to create multiple variables to
store multiple items. I will add one more state
capital to this list, Phoenix. Of course, if you
want distinct values stored in code, you will want
to avoid using a list. For example, if you make a
specific first and last name for someone playing a
game, you will want to store that information in
separate variables, as I have done here on lines
2 and 3. I will add a print statement on line
4 to print the list of capitals, and the list
prints just as written, with values in quotes,
separated by commas, in a set of square brackets.